haiya Sandra's my wonderful friend taya
Sanders of clover tribe
yes I'm excited to have you on here and
talk about Club attract I'm super
excited to welcome to the junkyard love
podcast it is amazing
down here everything yes yeah cuz you
thought before
yes definitely um do you see it I mean I
definitely painted the wall like I just
had my DJ stuff set up down here yeah I
mean I've seen it in stages I feel like
but it looks awesome doing here right
now cool I'm glad I very cozy
I'm glad you like it is it bigger or
smaller than the new place that you just
got yourself into
um it is about the same size maybe my
space might be a little bit bigger I
think yeah you know come more walls are
you excited about your new place I am so
excited it's a good day to record this
podcast cuz I'm on like cloud 9 about it
okay yeah well for new listeners let's
let's tell them about yourself you're
the owner of clover tribe but before we
get into that lets just hear a little
bit about taya Sanders okay
taya Sanders umm I am from Kelso
Washington I'm graduated from Kelso high
school went to Oregon State University
got my bachelor's in human development
and you can tell like I when people ask
about me I'm like oh this is my career
path that's how we are that's nothing
it's weird we've been talking about that
I'm here we're just like we feel like we
have to identify ourselves as just our
jobs yeah we're at work they're like oh
who are you and I'm like oh this is who
I am this is my background and I
graduated from Oregon State when a month
after I turned 20 years old so I was a
young I think actually I was the
youngest graduate at Oregon State to
graduate with a bachelor's degree which
is pretty cool yeah that's amazing
you've been doing like running sir else
you see all this you've always been like
five steps ahead yeah I I mean I don't
like to toot my own horn but toot too
bro I I've always been like very driven
I yeah I graduated high school with my
associates well
cheering I cheered in Albany and Tigard
and so people probably unless you're
from here don't know where that's at but
it was a long commute and I cheered
while going to school and I'll go into
school at LCCC and I held almost a full
time job during that whole y-yeah and
that was because I feel like I went to
way back in the day I think I went to a
couple of your cheer competitions those
were actually crazy like those yeah
there I traveled a lot like in the
United States I went to the world's
competition in Florida and I got a
couple injuries but I it was a huge huge
thing not just when people think of like
oh hey it was a cheerleader I'm like I
didn't like I mean yeah you do that's
like how you start out I think a lot of
people start out like that you know yeah
I actually didn't do any I was a gymnast
oh wait so you didn't do the high school
I didn't do any high school I was a
gymnast and then I did competitive cheer
and really like college cheerleading was
the first time I like actually said
cheers so it was different
I'm more of like a tumbler like in a
stumper and things like that yes I'm a
songwriter
all right cool so afterwards when did
you stop doing cheer so I had back
surgery when I was 17 I had a herniated
day or two herniated discs and I had one
rupture and so I then is where kind of I
thought my career was going to stop but
I worked through it and I ended up
cheering for Oregon State so that was
awesome
and I graduated what year did I graduate
from college
um 2015 so I stopped cheering 2014 yeah
and that is one thing I would love to
like it into I've had two kids total mom
bought but I would love like I can still
do backflips and
like I would love you know you feel like
you're gonna get a lot of it back oh
yeah yeah that's a li - it's muscle
memory and yeah
so I my boys think it's so cool when I
do flips so I'm like oh yeah dude
they're gonna just be a part or these
guys are gonna be I just went - I was
telling you I went to that the urban
warrior it's like American Ninja Warrior
they have like the padding's and the
monkey bars and the it's just super cool
hmm I feel like your boys would just rip
it up in there Oh Lincoln would love his
like favorite shows Ninja Warrior okay I
don't think I would be very well in the
Jory I thought that I did I went in
there man super cocky I'm like do they
have those like run up walls
yeah they do yeah and you're like I can
get to the top of that and you get
halfway up in his waist area and there's
there's like a the guy who shows you
around it was like this younger kid and
he's just a stud like he don't know if
his family owns it or what it was yeah
and he's just like he's acting more
mature than me in every way and he's
just getting really high up there and
he's telling us what to do so after
college I'm trying to think
after college I came back here I worked
for a mental health facility locally and
I actually got that job before I
graduated
um well at each stage of my life I
always held like one to two jobs
sometimes three while Jake my husband I
knew other Jake was trying to get
registered in his job I was the one that
was I worked at a head start so a
preschool class and I would do that and
then I would go work at a coffee shop
caffeine cafe local coffee shop I worked
there and then I would go coach cheer
lessons for little girls and Pratt do
private lessons and stuff and I'd also
babysit on the side cuz I didn't have
kids of my own so I'm like a total
workaholic
I'll work especially without kids oh my
gosh I didn't have kids at this point it
would be dangerous because all I do is
work and so I would even I would pick up
like house-sitting gigs and stuff and I
remember Jake
like oh my gosh Tia and I'm like it's
money it's money I can't say no Danny no
and what else am i doing I'm like
sitting here putting your skills though
right so I yeah I came back here worked
for mental health and I actually got on
at est 112 so that's who I worked for
the last four years and I worked with
at-risk youths in the community all
schools in calots County so that was an
amazing experience and it kind of it did
gear me up to what I want to do forever
right but there's this little thing
called from clover tribe hmm that's my
baby and I started doing that and I just
career how to be put on hold for a
little bit because I want to see where
this business goes yeah yeah okay so
when you first start a clover tribe what
was it well I was actually nine months
pregnant and I was walking with my mom
and I was well I mean like waddling
waddling yeah not even walking and I
want to say it was like a couple weeks
before my oldest Lincoln came and I was
like you know I really want like a baby
boutique or something like and at the
time there was not I know now there are
baby boutiques but at the time there
really wasn't here and I was having a
little boy and I was having a hard time
finding cool clothes for my baby to wear
a lot of like items that I was getting
were Carter's and it was like my friends
kids had them and yeah you know you're
just like oh you want your kids you want
to have something different yeah yeah
and so um I remember kind of just like
discussing it with my mom and like her
and I both were like oh my gosh that
would be so cool like she could do like
screen printing or something like that
and I could do and at the time I did not
know how to sew at all I mean it was
like oh yeah I could probably figure it
out what experience did you have in like
screen printing or any of that
my mom has experience doing that with um
she like the Kelso wrestling she he does
all helps out with all of that stuff so
she could totally do that
but from myself I didn't that would be
my part of the gig would be like the
handmade clothes and stuff and at at
that time I didn't really think like oh
I could buy stuff off a wish and then
mark it up for something it was like
know if I'm gonna do it it's gonna be
like handmade it's gonna be unique it's
gonna be good quality so it was because
I my personality is like I'm the kind of
person that when I like see something or
when I get an idea like I will go for it
okay um or when I want something I'm
trying to get better about it but when I
want something it's like oh I will go
get it
trying to get better at it trying to get
better at it it might be in Seattle but
I'll drink if they're if my local store
doesn't have it like I'm I don't know
just when I have my mind set on
something I'll I want it
same thing was like when I have a goal
like I will reach it and I won't stop
until I reach it so when this kind of
idea came about the last couple weeks of
my pregnancy I was kind of thinking like
you know that I could totally do this
and it didn't actually start until I had
my son so you're just you're two weeks
before giving birth and you're like
let's see I think I just do this right
now is the time yeah
okay any distraction away from like that
miserable last two weeks start a
business right yeah so yeah any listener
that's very getting stressed out yeah
start a business doesn't matter how
close you gotta play and I threw my I
worked at yes you won twelve during that
time and I actually got summer off so I
had my son in May and actually got that
whole summer off it's not a fan of this
cat sex I know dude I just I closed it
or okay what was I saying oh I worked at
ESD at the time and I had my son in May
and I worked up until I had him but then
I got that entire summer off because I
worked for the schools so I hadn't
he'll like mid-august off so after I had
my son all they I mean all newborns do
is like sleep I mean they're they're
pretty I don't know well you don't do
much know just gonna have to be like
present like around ready yeah right and
you know they're like connected to you
but like as far as like recovering and
stuff like I I could not sit like at all
so maternity leave is what drove me
crazy and I went bought her machine and
I was like I'm gonna teach myself how to
sell okay you just pulled up YouTube or
what you start doing YouTube all YouTube
mm-hmm what's your sewing machine is it
like it's a some crazy fancy one in
there um I've upgraded since then but um
I just have a serger I do have a sewing
machine too but I do like everything you
notice serger is I think I know of it I
think and I know that it exists I
couldn't point one out in a crowd so
it's not like a typical like sewing
machine it's like it does I mean I'm
trying to think like the inside of your
clothes like your shirt that seems right
that's like a serger yeah I mean I
worked at mr. formal for for some years
and something was going and visiting you
there yeah
I mean it was a lot of just like the
most half-assed way I could so back then
but I don't know I'm sure he had
interactions with these things yeah I'd
have to like show you I don't really
know like obviously I'm totally YouTube
learned that's right you to YouTube
taught so I don't know like really you
know the terms and stuff I'm just kind
of like turns out you don't really have
to to get the job done with hate right
exactly yeah so I oh my gosh I can't
even explain to you how frustrating self
teaching yourself how to do that though
it took because I I don't know not like
things come easy to me
but in the past like things we just came
easy to me I can do it and this oh like
threading the machine even like it would
take me 45 minutes to thread the machine
and I would be like saying choice words
which my husband now like laughs at me
because he's like you know I thread it
in like 30 seconds if that maybe 15
seconds
and he's like remember that one time he
threw the thing out the window
Oh literally like not physically out the
window but I I was like raging
postpartum like yeah so Jake right so
yeah I started during my maternity leave
and that's when like I remember I I
didn't sell right away obviously I can't
sell do it so it took me I want to
say a couple months of trying to like
trial and error with fabrics and things
and thankfully I had like a little model
I had like a tiny little baby putting
him in another clothes please let me
sleep mom yeah he didn't fight me so I'm
like oh cool so I got to kind of like
you know trial and error like what
fabric-like material that I liked amber
your first like your very first design
someone's we were like this is awesome
were you like made it was done and
you're like woah oh my gosh I can't even
tell you like the success so at first I
didn't buy any patterns which that was
really stupid okay but I I tried to like
make my own patterns I didn't want to
spend money like on patterns and
patterns are like 10 bucks each so you
don't want to like go too far into it
and I don't know at the time I was like
I'm just gonna just experimenting try to
learn how to do it yeah so I would cut
up pears that I bought like from a store
and I would like trace the them and make
my own patterns so I didn't really like
YouTube taught me like obviously certain
things but when it came to my pattern
that I created like it was all trial and
error and so I remember like and it's
like funny to think about but I remember
like when I made so I'm like this is it
I would oh my god I'm on to something
like I got it like and once you made one
it's like okay you know how to do it now
remember the item was like pants er it
was pants so that's what I started out
with and now I'm making like I can sew
like sweatshirts and crew necks and I
mean if I have a pattern I can really so
I feel like anything
especially like baby clothes related
it's just a lot more helpful when you
have a powder nothing wrong with that I
mean I used templates in my music
production stuff and my DJing and stuff
I'll use templates or if I'm feeling
like I'm like I can't grasp what's kind
of said I should be making I'll kind of
listen to like someone else is 30-minute
mix and I'm like oh yeah okay let's try
to get that kind of vibe within 30
minutes for this show so I feel like
that's kind of so I earn I cut it out I
make one of them and I'm like okay this
is what I don't like about it so then I
completely tweak it so I do end up
making it into like my own but at that
time when I had first started I didn't
have any patterns and so I remember you
know I I got pretty fast at it confident
and then I would break a needle or
something and then I'd go back to
youtube because I'm like how do I change
a needle right yeah I'd have to switch
which for awhile it I hated changing out
the thread in my machine so when you're
sewing like a black shirt you want to
treat change to black thread and not why
it's right or it'll show through and
like just the different like settings
for like how loose your stitches and
there's like so much behind it that yeah
it's not super simple no at first I was
like oh I could probably do it but over
like it is it has taken me so long I'm
still learning and that was Lincoln's
three and a half how old was he when you
were just try it like first starting
when you at this time when you had like
these awesome pants like these are so
cool um couple weeks old yes
yeah I mean once I got like the idea I
was like okay I'm going for it and then
you just started going to town and
making a million pairs of pants yeah and
it took me a while before I like would
sell I started sewing say may 2016 I'm
like when's my kid's birthday
now that you have two like two kids I'm
like okay this one's 18 this one's 16 um
but so 2016 May 2016
I didn't start selling stuff until
August 2016 and I remember I was like
okay I'm gonna make a website instead of
just like oh post
Instagram or Facebook it's not really
back when like that was super popular as
a cam and I do like my website instead
of doing like an Etsy why wouldn't I do
Etsy so much easier it's weird to also
think about the it is way different now
just in those few years yeah the things
you are talking about are relevant to
point out that it wasn't like that
actually no I mean now you can like post
anything like oh I made a sugar scrub
does anybody want to buy it and people
will buy it like back then I don't know
I guess I didn't really try but it
wasn't I think it would be kind of
scrolled past it wouldn't be yeah for
sure just a different world for sure but
yeah I remember my pants
I like look at him now and I'm like oh
my gosh cuz I still have like some of
the first pairs that I made and just so
you know remind myself where I can even
probably just hang them on the wall you
sucked
now you don't write it's like okay like
yeah I came very far but I've also sewn
so many items yeah you're so I feel like
you'll text me all the time you'll be
listening to the podcast he'll text me
like I'm doing my sewing tonight you're
solving literally every night hours and
hours yeah and once I I've tried to like
wake up okay I'm gonna go to sleep early
I'm gonna wake up at like you know 4:30
and I'm gonna sew until my kids wake up
738 or the days that I work like I'm
gonna sew until I have to start getting
ready so then I can put kind of like a
time limit on how long I'm sewing but
once you get into that like it's so hard
to stop so that's why I choose to sew at
night put my kids down and then I just
like listen to my podcasts yep have your
own time yeah like that's my I mean I
just so until my basically I'll I'll
walk to bed and I'll just pull up on my
bed and Jake's like I'm like I work
myself until I I physically have to go
to bed yep and they just keep sewing in
your dreams a little bit a little bit
yeah and then I wake up in the morning
like okay I didn't get this done but I'm
trying to switch my okay so jumping from
when you decided to go all-in because at
the beginning here we're talking
you're just like you're making it for
your kid you're making it because you're
like this is pretty cool but you weren't
thinking like this is so I'm gonna quit
my job soon and do this oh gosh no this
honestly I've always been the kind of
person there's some people out there
which I'm not like judgmental at all
like if you wanna be a stay-at-home mom
do you that's awesome I you're so
fortunate to be able to do that kind of
thing for me I am such a workaholic that
I would drive myself crazy if I was a
stay-at-home mom with nothing to do
which granted us taking care of your
children are its full-time job right
full-time job but for me I just I've got
to have something I can't just sit do
you think all like the the spaces in
between so people in the same position
the spaces in between where they're like
you know trying to get a couple minutes
to relax and watch TV or grab a bite or
whatever it is like when we're trying to
always get these moments in between of
people raising their kids I think it is
very beneficial what you do rather than
trying to distract or like going on
social media and numbing or going on TV
and just like watching TV for a few
hours while the kids are sleeping I know
that probably feels really great once am
I should totally do it I'm sure you do
but I think what's even more healing to
us is to feel you know more calibrated
to to our real self and you do that well
by sitting down yeah it's me time it's
low state if you think about it I mean
it's for you it's it's weird like I I
get so much joy out of it like it
doesn't feel like oh I'm gonna go work
another six hour shift
seven hour shift at night after I put my
kids down for bed it's like I look
forward to that time recharging in the
way yeah and I listen to my podcasts
like that's the time that I listen my
podcast my I mean I used to watch like
YouTube videos and stuff a while sewing
but I've never really been like a TV
show watcher more like a movie or
anything like that so like those people
like they get their me time they drink a
glass of Rose a on the couch or wine or
something like that I I just fall asleep
I get right I get bored I'm not TV
asleep time that's what I think yeah I
just in my couch do you have the same
couches I do always in the same way
thank you
yes I just fall asleep so for me it's
like okay I'm gonna go that's my me time
that's my hobby that's even if I'm not
even like making money like that's I
genuinely enjoy doing it and so um yeah
I yeah the the art of like practicing
something and non-stop obviously having
the drive of like cool I could make this
a business this would be really cool but
just noticing you notice this feels nice
this isn't exactly what I figured on
doing you know Here I am it was at first
I was like okay I'm gonna work my
full-time job and I'm going to do this
as a little side gig just for extra
money and it was never I did think like
okay that would be cool to go down to
like part-time or something if this does
grow to be something but I never ever
ever thought that I would quit my job
and do this full-time
and guess what I'm on week two okay so
so let's jump to here where you're at
now you started out just making a couple
clothes and now you're you just kind of
a store location oh yeah a location
outside of my house so I will say 2019
well honestly I used to I've never been
able to like set boundaries since
starting this business it's like once I
I've never taken a break or anything
I've had another baby since then I was
sewing
well actually I was sewing for him the
night before I had him because he didn't
have anything we're in the hospital I
was sewing for everyone else's kids so I
was sewing the night before I had him
and then I get home and after ledger so
ledger was born in 2018
and I tried I was like okay I'm gonna
take like a month off or something it's
it's a piece of me it's like I I
couldn't take time away even though I
probably looking back I should have but
I was like nope I'm right back to it and
like I said newborn stage granted I had
a - he was 2 years old when I had Ledger
so almost two and a half
um so it's a little bit busier but it's
like that was my me time once ledger
both Lincoln and ledger went to sleep
I'm gonna show a couple things
although newborn stage they don't
they're up every couple hours and so I
couldn't stay up like seven hours a
night
but I'd stay up normally until like his
first wake up which would be like 11
o'clock or 12 o'clock and then I would
feed him lay him down and then I would
go to bed so yeah I've never been able
to really like set boundaries with
sewing 2019 though was very busy just in
all aspects of my life I start just like
letting it rip itself like letting let's
see what happens who wants orders I'll
make him yeah I I mean I would launch
something I'd be selling something
almost every single day something or
multiple items I was doing you know
events but I was also I had two babies
at home like Lincoln wasn't even three
yet and I had ledger and that transition
from one kid to two kids is hard like I
think I I don't know I underestimated
that one kid you feel like supermom I
know for me I was like wow I got this I
could have ten kids like Lincoln was a
good baby though but once two kids came
your two-year-old was I mean roller
coaster of adjusting you have a new baby
it was a lot on top of me working
outside of the home and you know I can't
give up my business okay so at that time
I feel like if I wasn't serious about
doing this I would stop doing it or like
take a break but I can't I couldn't like
I think about it all the time like I
think oh my gosh my customers like
they're gonna what are they gonna think
if I just don't you know fall off I
think they're gonna be okay I know but
my heart is like of course like my
customers like they are so loyal to me
I have like an amazing little butt yeah
it and they're all you know moms some of
them obviously like they buy for gifts
and they're just supporters like any
like like share comment anything like
that is amazing but a lot of the people
like I've gotten to like be friends with
through this business because they're
moms too and obviously I mean you're not
a mom but um it's weird like when you
become a mom you lose like a lot of
friends you you don't really you can't
just drop everything and go you know do
things anymore right it's and I know
like everyone's busy in life but it's
like when you're a mom it's like it's a
huge change oh my gosh I can't even like
explain to you it's an amazing change
though you don't feel the need to like
but friendship-wise it's it's sad and
depressing and for this like with this
business I I found such like a fast like
quick community because they were all
moms that were purchasing from me and it
was weird because it was like oh my gosh
my mom frizzy
yes I'm like migrating towards mom
friends and it's like them we would have
playdates together and things like that
so um yeah my loyal customers it was
hard for me to like drop off because
then it's like oh my gosh like yeah yeah
I understand that I mean we were talking
about though like me when I went off
social media I mean I wasn't like super
planned about it I was just going
through my emotional things out loud
just had to I I was telling you like I
missed out on a ton of gigs like my I
was like I'm off social media trying to
get just better feel better and you know
I have a DJ company and like people
wanting me to deejay their weddings and
DJ this thing and that thing those
messages just got left you know the last
year yeah and it's like I got first I
did have like I was like stressed about
it I was like I can't get rid of social
media I can't like that's my business
and what are they gonna think and blah
blah blah but I think that the world is
a bit more understanding now of not
having to be connected 24/7 I will say
like when I announced like I'm going to
take a
break to spend time with my family or I
just I'm still like I my website still
closed and it's been closed since I
think I closed it like the 19th of
December so it's been almost a month and
people are like very supportive about it
they're like oh yeah you know that's so
awesome that you're spending time with
your boys and things like that and it is
a big transition like over the last
month it's been a big transition
business-wise and putting my job and
things like that so I'm just trying to
and we're about to sell our house so
it's like everyday I have a lot of
things that I'm still doing you just
don't really enjoy half-assing anything
no yeah not at all and I do that's one
thing I'm working on because do you what
are you on India Graham I feel like I
was like a 9 1 or 1 9 okay it's like a
peacemaker
I'm infj on the thumb is Briggs okay so
I'm an achiever and I'm I'm listening to
like you know podcast I got a book I
haven't read it yet I listened to the
audible so like while I'm sewing and I'm
trying to work on though since I am an
achiever I need to slow down and be
content with where I'm at right like
that's a huge thing for me is it's
always like okay what's next what's next
what's next I mean there was one year
and Jake and I his relationship was at
2015 I graduated from school or no we
bought our first house I graduated from
school we got married we got pregnant or
I got pregnant and then Jake moved up in
his job we bought like a new car like it
was like by the end of that year I was
like oh my gosh like we did a lot of
yeah then the next year is like okay
what's next and that's just my mindset
and I'm really trying to like work on
that because I need to for my well-being
I need to be like okay I think it's a
lot of us man a lot of us like are we're
not too far apart in age it's just kind
of how we've been brought up we're
always just like okay kiddies Nick come
on come on look at you we're always like
you're going to high school so you can
do good in college you're go
- you know the this thing before this
thing yeah you gotta remember oh yeah
I'm building life right now and it's
enjoyable I think I'm vining for you for
me though when I don't have something
that I'm working towards I fall into a
really big slump mm-hmm like yeah yeah I
can't just just be stag no or I feel
like I'm a piece of but yeah but
but you have to be able to look at so
like look at what you just named I mean
you guys had an incredible few years and
you accomplished a lot that not a ton of
people around your age and with all the
things going on have accomplished so you
do have to be able to find things and
you are getting better at it and you're
working on these things we text about it
all the time at like oh shoot okay like
what Jake and I have done is great yeah
like we're like like what we've built is
great and this is wonderful and almost
like it's corny as it sounds like just
like let's take a mental picture of this
time in my life inertia and I think you
are getting better about that we were
kind of sending like Tony Robbins stuff
yes back and forth yes I am getting
better I'm just
that's one of my when I'm am sewing like
it's nice because I get to work on my
self too because I'm listening to
audibles and things like that
and so that's one thing though that I'm
like I need to be content with so it is
taking me a little bit like I have a
website launch planned and I was totally
hoping that that website launch would
already be launched right now yeah but
I'm like you know what I'm getting my
space figured out I'm doing this I'm
doing that I got a couple samples of new
fabrics in because I'm you know I want
to I do like bamboo fabric and so it's
higher quality wash where things like
that like you can wash because babies
have blowouts and their food and you
know that they're you get stained up
like crazy so I just got in the mail the
last two days samples of fabrics and
it's like I'm just gonna take the time
to you know work out the little things
and and then I'm gonna do this website
launch versus before I'm like oh my gosh
I feel the stress like and need to do a
website launch right now when sometimes
you would come P company stuff with so
like at the podcast I'm like because I
have my
website and it's like half-assed done
and I'm still it's under construction
you know but I would not even post my
podcast because I'm like oh I don't want
to post it on my websites done because I
wanna show my dick but it's like well
people can go to Spotify and can go
table music and go in and listen to it
but a lot of times I would use like
building this big thing as my failure to
even start so at least you've kept
yourself going yeah and each day
especially now that I'm not working I
keep like we're going back to that
because it's like crazy how much stuff
I'm getting done each day I have like I
I looked at almost 10 spaces the last
two days with my kids and it's like
everything on the car
pretty easy honestly because it's like
without work and stuff it's like I my
patients everything I'm like happy I'm
happy and it's it's doing something like
for my future that I'm so stoked about
so it's like I don't even care if it's
pouring rain and I'm getting my kids out
of the car like they're having so much
fun like let's stop and puddles on the
way there like I I think that that
moment is I mean that's a huge thing if
you think about it a lot of us we do get
so caught up and just dredging in our
sand yes like pushing yeah and it is
Neisseria dude even just going to check
out these spots is so good cuz
everything combined to what I'm doing
here makes me feel good and for sure
that even that it's raining it feels
great exactly and I think over I keep
saying this to 2019 just was not like it
was are we still had successes and good
times and stuff but as far as like my
mental state like I got stretched so
thin yeah and it was mainly like I did
it to myself I was working I had
expectations at work I was taking on
extra things like a couple parenting
classes could you describe kind of what
outside of Chloe tried before clever try
for your degree work what what exactly
is it can you expand on what you were
doing at work yeah so my degree is human
development in psychology of a minor in
psychology and I would work with at-risk
youth so students that were at risk for
mainly dropping out of school and so it
was a lot of
I mean I've seen a lot of horrible
things and but I I loved being like that
person that got down and and talked
one-on-one like dude what's going on
versus being another you know
authoritative figure in somebody else's
life or in that student's life saying
you know come on if you're not gonna
graduate then you're gonna be a piece of
press your life and things like that so
I did love I loved my job but where I'm
at in my just motherhood and I think if
I didn't have my business I'm like oh I
I could have totally stayed in that
position yeah I love it
and my company um actually like offered
me this like big new program that they
are have in the works to be drug and
alcohol so I would run like a drug and
alcohol treatment facility inside the
school in the local school district and
that was so cool and an amazing
opportunity and they wanted me to do it
so bad they wanted to send me to a
training in California in February and
and at first I was like yes like that's
amazing huge pay increase like I'm still
on school district schedule but I I did
I think you do like a couple weeks
because obviously treatment doesn't stop
in the summertime and so you you have
like part-time hours in the summer you
still get like winter break Christmas
break things like that but your drug and
alcohol counselor within the school
district that I graduated at like that's
so cool because I do feel like I mean
this community I've moved away and I've
came back and it's yeah it's my
community like I'm I'm here to like give
back to my community is cool I love it
it's cool getting older and because I
feel like I was I didn't like hate where
I came from by any means but I just had
like a I mean I didn't like hate it from
an outside perspective but I just didn't
really even like talk about like I just
like I swear I live whatever yeah but as
I've gotten older and I'm like oh yeah I
can be a part of the commuter everyone
I'm sure you can really like everyone's
like oh I can't wait to get out of here
I can't wait to get out of here and that
was me like I moved away granted I had
like my boyfriend or
other now-husband here so I was like I'm
most likely gonna come back to Kelso of
course but a huge piece of me was like
this is my community like and there's so
many kids especially that need help like
in our community and so that opportunity
came about I want to say over this
summer about September and it was gonna
be a lot of work for me like we are
starting up this program and from the
ground up myself and like my team
basically and it's very um what's the
word a high burnout like being drug and
alcohol like and some people it's funny
how like blinded they are to it it's
like oh you know are there really sixth
graders doing drug drugs and alcohol
like are they drinking or I'm like yeah
I had a student seriously have a dirty
way for meth in the sixth grade like
it's it's bad and it's bad everywhere
I'm not saying it's just our community
but myself like this community has
offered me a lot and so I feel the need
to come back and help but around that
time that my business was going great I
so normally like 20 to 30 hours a week
on top of working and so I'm spread
pretty thin especially I have two kids
at home that I mean total momma's boys'
like I do everything for them my
husband's amazing but my boys just want
me like they want to be glued to me and
and so at that point I was like gosh you
know taking on this new adventure I
would love to do it and it's a huge pay
raise and stuff but is that where my
heart's at right mm-hmm
I don't know so I think kind of around
that time is when I just kind of
mentally like you took a look at the
momentum that you had gained I think
yeah and just everything
while my thought was okay I'm gonna do
this I'm gonna do this I'm gonna balance
at all also taking this new position I
would have to go back to school so mom
or school on top of it all I would and
it's only like nine months or so but
it's night classes away from my boys so
that was one more thing that it was like
okay can i balance it all and everyone
around me is like you're amazing you can
balance it all and I'm like I probably
could balance at all but my self-care
yeah see that's the thing is you gotta
take a look at it completely being
everybody around you is like you're
amazing you're awesome you can do this
and you're like okay I can do it I mean
but you got to be able to take a look at
yourself and like what's best for me
what's best for my boys what's best for
me yeah I think what's best for my
family
exactly exactly so at that time I was
just like I don't know if I can so I
brought it to my husband's attention I
was like babe I I really don't think
like I don't know if I can do it he's
like baby whatever you know Jake was on
your side oh my gosh she's so sweet -
he's so like you know I'll support you
in anything that you do and and I was
like you know I got this crazy idea like
what if I were to quit my job and he's
like baby I know baby I know anything
that you do you set your mind to and so
I was like okay I mean I guess I'm
thinking about it so I we thought about
it for probably a good three months
before I and I don't know if it kind of
had to do with like deep down I wanted
to do it and so when I would become
overwhelmed I would just like lose
control and I almost I'm like I I want
this so bad so it's like I can't I'm
like making myself not be able to
balance at all
does that make sense no yeah you know I
was like self-sabotaging yes and it's
like almost at the point where it's like
cuz I want this you gotta let yourself
have it at some point yeah and so um the
last couple months of the year we're
we're just hard it was my busiest season
for sowing my I coordinated because you
know why wouldn't I cord
small shops out are they pop up in the
middle of all of this stuff I have were
you nine months pregnant just by chance
at this point no thank goodness I made
it through 2019 without getting pregnant
I don't know if you remember my post my
new year's resolution for going into
2019 was to not get pregnant it's a good
start so because I had been pregnant
like for like four years yeah are you
guys planning to have more kids I do
want one more but I want to Jake's like
gonna listen to this and be like haha
because it's very very busy with my boys
they are I mean balls to the wall like
they're crazy they're anything like your
brothers were right so you remember my
little brother it's like having two of
those and they're only two a little over
tuna or a little under two and a half
years apart and so they and they year
I'm hoping this year is gonna be the
year of them getting along cuz it's been
just a transition for all of us but um I
do want one more so that was another
thing when thinking like about future
you know do I want to dive into this new
career when ultimately I do want to have
another baby right in the next couple
years you certainly can't have it all
figured out right at this second that's
for sure I mean it's good that you think
ahead and you have to you have to think
of things as more than just and I know I
can't plan like okay I'm gonna have a
baby um we're gonna conceived on August
2nd right it is for my strikes yeah it
doesn't work like that but um I we do
one another but I want to be I need to
work on myself first right and like I
totally we are like yes that's gonna be
our last baby we want to have everything
kind of slowed down and our boys do I
feel like each like Lincoln and Leger
both like low-key kind of want to be
like only child or like only just those
are they have like only child syndrome
is what it's called yeah so I'm like hey
they need like a little extra time to
you know have each other and like before
we
have another kid I don't want to rush it
so I don't care how far apart like
ledger in our last one are I will just
want to enjoy perfect everything I think
that's a great start and then you know
wherever life brings you after that it's
gonna happen I think that I really enjoy
you know you're building yourself into
your this wonderful person you have all
these things that you've accomplished
but you're building yourself into your
like now how do I be a business owner
it's like this new thing really and yeah
and you've been you listen to like
audiobooks and you check out like the
motivational YouTube stuff and you
listen to all these like things I think
it's just super cool how you're you're
taking on the new role of business owner
but you're like I'm not gonna half-ass
that either like it's like don't think
that this thing that's different that
I've been what I've been working towards
is gonna go any different so you're
improving yourself what what are you
doing what are some little things that
you're doing that seem to be improving
you and making you slow down and so my
kind of sentence of the year kind of
thing is because I've always been like
working myself to the core so I'm like
you know what this is my year to work
smarter not harder
that's like my my thing okay and you
know if I have to so one thing I'm like
okay if I raise my prices two dollars a
dollar something like that like making
little changes that it's like okay if I
do that it'll be a little less sewing
and it really won't make a difference to
people that it's a dollar you know so
things like that and now I'm going full
force I just got a space I'm thinking
about you know doing like pop-ups
monthly and cuz now I'm also the person
that I always have to have an income for
me not for myself but I have to be
contributing to my family yeah yeah and
it's like a thing in me it's like hey
I'm gonna pay for this this this and so
now that I quit my job and I don't have
a paycheck
every last day of the month it's a
little scary because it's like wow now
this side gig money yes I actually have
to
you know be making money now so I'm
going full force into planning my
finances and I got like a business tax
person I hired her because I don't know
that's why I've always kept it like a
side gig a hobby cuz I'm like I do not
want any I don't want to have to do any
of that more money the financial the
taxes I'm not that kind of person I
rather do the work
I rather so my fingers off I don't want
to have to do any of that and so um I a
friend of mine that is also a business
owner he was at the small shop Saturday
event with me and he was like hey you've
got it if you're gonna do this like
you've got to hire like somebody and
then you have all that time to sew and
they're doing that for a small chunk of
you know money each month but it'll be
way less stressful
that's good balance there yeah so I'm
like okay and that has been awesome
because I'm starting this business I got
my business license I'm I got I have
write-offs now things like that that I'm
like okay I have no idea what to do
she's taking care of all that so that's
one thing that's a lot less stressful on
me going forward is she's handling that
I'm setting boundaries so like I used to
so until 3:00 4:00 in the morning
I'm like okay I need to at least get
eight hours of sleep obviously I have
like my own list of like personal
self-care resolutions right and I'm
trying to go one at a time so they
actually happen versus looking at all
the whole list but that's one thing is
don't you yes that's one thing I'm like
I need more sleep because I am a very
anxious person when I wake up in the
morning if I don't get sleep and I
function off of like little sleep I
don't want to make that a habit though
but yes like I function off of a couple
hours of sleep and I I do fine but I
know like eventually that has I'm not
even gonna say that is going to catch up
that
I was caught up to me right to the point
where my mental breakdown December was
like I that's one thing I have to change
is I need more sleep I need to set
boundaries I need to every chance I get
at home I don't need to be running up
and sewing stuff and that's one thing
like having the business at my house it
was like okay they're sitting for a
second I'm gonna run up and so really
quick right I'm just gonna get one order
done really quick or you know they're
doing this I'm gonna run up really quick
my husband's got the kids for a second
I'm gonna do this versus just being like
present mm-hmm and cuz I can already
tell like they are appreciating the
happier mom that I am like the more
patience it's so cool like obviously
it's been like a couple weeks so I can't
say oh my gosh it's like life-changing
but so far it is like pretty profound at
the beginning I'm sure yes they are they
are happier and it's like I'm not
running up and I'm not my my patience is
just I mean it's crazy in your attention
span of like I always talk about
attention spans with our phones like
you're talking to someone and then also
you pulled out of it by a text message
and I mean even just the thoughts of
like oh crap I need to go get this done
you're hanging out with your kid but in
the back of your mind you're like oh
honey to run upstairs really quick so
that's just less present exactly like
I'm like especially bedtime rushing
bedtime was one thing that I did with
both the boys like they would be like
mom used to call me like mommy's not
coming and I'm like but I can't tonight
I'm sorry I love you bye
and why it's because I had to go so
because I had orders pending orders it
was that I mean that's kind of like in a
long way like putting someone else's
family before yours in a you know
strange way right yeah I mean ultimately
like putting especially my business like
and I I was gone working all day like he
hadn't seen me
I spent from 5 o'clock to let's say 8
o'clock because they'd go to bed at 8
o'clock 5 to 8 I they're all like I'm
all theirs but really that's only like
three hours it's like I now I'm like
Bubba I'm gonna single you and I'm gonna
fall asleep in your bed like
why not why not that's great and that's
so nice
being able to just set those boundaries
like and I hope I stick to it I'm sure I
mean it's it's things come and go I mean
maybe for a few weeks you're not going
to be able to but just being able to be
as you are right now I'm like okay I'm
noticing that I'm doing those things
yeah I kinda want to slow him down
yeah I'm pretty I'm pretty self-aware
with things like over the last year I'm
like okay this this this this has
brought me to this like I'm pretty self
aware of things like I don't let myself
hit too deep I I make sure to like I
notice the things does that make sense
don't look up like I'm like okay I need
to make these changes as soon as
possible or I might have a total mental
breakdown and so yeah that I'm trying to
think what else what was the question
again I was just asking about things
that you do to to get better and improve
and become a business owner yeah so
setting boundaries um
setting like set kind of schedules is my
plan so I will be at my office space
three days a week at least I'd say like
three days a week where I'm doing
business and that's far more than I've
ever gotten normally I just do it after
hours after bedtime and so I'm like wow
what can I get done in three and three
days right like wow you just get in the
zone there today and I do understand
like that was another stressor for me it
was childcare so I understand things are
gonna come up with my baby sick or
something I might not so that day but I
might flex it for like when Jake's home
on the weekend a day I might flex it and
he stays home with the kids while I go
so that day to make up for it right so I
think just communicating like with him
on like you know my schedule for the
week too because he can kind of help me
like hold me accountable a little bit
right so I don't overwork myself because
he's totally like I want to just chill
and watch a movie and I'm like that's a
like because I kind of find myself like
well I'm gonna go edit a podcast and I'm
like run downstairs like you do it on
the
that's what I do so well sometimes I'll
do that but I'm not I'm not good at
distractions like if she starts talking
to me I'll bet he'll be like I need my
space and I'm kind of prissy about it
but just you know it's okay like like
you know we're here to live this life we
want to accomplish great things and
that's awesome and we're going to yes
slow down and enjoy your life in between
um hey I didn't want to ask you
clover tribe the name I was curious
about how how you even came across that
yeah um so you know when I was nine
months pregnant because I actually I
knew that I would
I wanted to eventually start selling
things um but I didn't like obviously it
took months for me to get to that point
but I was like I need a name like I want
a name and like a because I think a
piece of me is like I always wanted to
be kind of like a little business owner
or something and at that time it was
kind of like it was before a lot of
people started doing it but it was kind
of the beginning of it where people were
doing like little side gigs and stuff
and so I sat down and my family is super
Irish and I just remember like writing
out kind of a list of words that kind of
described like my family or my
upbringing or like my favorite words
things like that yeah it was weird
I had no kids at the time so I had like
a lot more like time to just do those
kind of things to sit down and draw
those news yeah
so I sat and I made like a pretty long
list I remember it like vividly in my
head it was on a spiral notebook and
then I knew for some weird reason that I
wanted a plus sign in the middle like I
want a plus sign and so I had like a
plus and then I had another list and so
I knew I wanted it to be like two words
with a plus sign which is kind of weird
cuz clover tribe but like it has the
plus sign in the middle so people always
think it's clover and tribe which I've
kind of adapted I'm like clover and
tried yeah yeah and so but at the time
it was like having have one word and
then the other so I picked I picked
tribe first because I'm like you know
kids kids clothes like it to raise a kid
to raise a family things like that you
need your
and it almost has turned into be like my
little community of moms that I have
like that's my tribe hmm and so it's I
love that I picked that I will never
rebrand because I love my name but um so
I picked that and then I had my little
plus sign and then I was going through
all these words and it just kind of
stuck to me I was like clover and tribe
like clover tribe that's perfect
and so I remember I like highlighted it
as like a I'm going for that and I got
on Etsy and I looked at a little logos I
remember I bought like a four dollar
logo and I have like I have had somebody
revamp my logo and stuff since then that
was a little investment that I did for
myself last year but yeah that's how I
got my name yeah yeah I like that that's
cool I at the beginning of when I did my
name it was uh I think I mentioned
another podcast it was technically a
lyric from a Lupe Fiasco song but it was
like in the middle of the verse or
something and it but it just stood out
to me and I don't really even
particularly remember but it's funny
every time so I was like what's junkyard
love and I said lovely you explained it
in that podcast I listened to it well
every time I explain it it's like kind
of different I feel like yeah but it's
still but people like okay I get it yeah
so is I didn't understand your name at
first I mean I I liked it not like I was
like oh what's that but I was like oh
yeah junker I'd loved and then when you
explained it in that podcast I was like
wow that's awesome I don't even remember
what I said the JA you know like the car
parts in the junkyard oh right okay yeah
yeah that's a nice each each thing like
somebody's gonna take one piece out of
it all right you know yeah yeah yeah the
parts in the in the junkyard or not by
themselves they're not useful but yes
for one person these parts are
particularly exactly what they are
looking for yeah I was like yeah no it's
cool it's cool you know letting yourself
you know kind of kind of dream
you know we hear stuff like that right
here like dream in in it's almost like
see that the annotation I put on it with
my voice we almost kind of want to make
fun of it anyway right we don't want to
call it corny but I think that it really
is important for the way our brains work
to have kind of like a goal like a you
know you're like I could I could do this
you know what I'm like heck yeah and
then you have awesome people in your
life like your mom was willing to help
you and Jake obviously is like hell yeah
baby let's do it yeah right yeah it's
really cool to take you know I ideas and
in what ifs and turn them into I think
especially with our like podcasts and
our the motivational I mean when I even
take like a couple days off of not
listening to something it's weird right
I'm like I mean and then when I listen
I'm just like oh my gosh the motivation
I'm like let's kill it like I it's weird
we were talking about like I think I
when I wake up it I mean so I'm on a
youtube break right now is telling you
but for a long time in something I'd do
probably more often more days than I
don't just for the last like year and a
half is I wake up and within probably
five to ten minutes I have some sort of
like a motivational something going on
background like it you can go on YouTube
and type motivational and they put a new
one up pretty much every day you know
it's Tony Robbins with some music behind
it in whatever it's it's cool because it
kind of like locks you into that that
momentum of moving forward yeah that is
also like something that I take time for
myself is when I'm because I we have a
DVD player in our car and so I'm always
listening to cars or monsters ink or a
Toy Story or something like I never get
to listen to music or podcasts like in
my car which a lot of people that's
where they listen to it at I don't
because I have to listen to you know I
can spit quotes from all of those movies
because I'm just listening to it yeah
Jake thinks it's funny cuz when we get
in the car it's like we'll say stuff the
movies not even on the kids are just
like you guys shut up exactly so that's
like if I get like 10 minutes to myself
to like go run the target
back I'll listen to something because
it's like my break away from the kids
I get like same thing was like going up
to my so room and having that time it's
like when I'm driving in the car it's
like when I'm listening to my
inspirational it's not Mike Wazowski yes
literally in my we upgraded to monsters
University oh that's a great choice too
yeah seems kind of old at this point but
I mean kids don't really know what's
like super news you know what his
favorite movie is um
Rookie of the Year you know that one I
want to say they're like 1987 or
something um it had a baseball on it and
it was a five dollar movie at Target and
one of the times I had picked I let him
pick something out I was like oh five
bucks okay and he loved dicks it was
baseball I literally had that in the car
DVD player for six months replaying like
Jake and I can quote it word for word I
don't know these are the things that
when people tell me about I'm like I'm
not ready to be a parent there's I'll
lose my mind like I like I have to play
certain songs like six times a year at
clubs in home but like you're like yeah
Lincoln um he like when he gets obsessed
with the movie we watch it like over and
over and over and over like the grinch
four and it wasn't just for Christmas
it's been like mm-hmm months
we watched the Grinch can we just at
least do a different season yeah bring
around it the nice thing is we went from
the old Grinch to the new Grinch anyway
the time of the creator like he had to
soundtrack what is it is it Kid Cudi or
Tyler is it kid it might be Kenny I
don't know yeah so that's my jam cuz I'm
like mr. Grinch oh yeah yeah yeah that
one was cool we actually I didn't fully
watch it but I watched a little bit of a
scaly was washing it so we can kind of
back you know go back and forth but it's
still like the Grinch yeah so that's
about as crazy as easy not being I mean
but now dude you got your own you got
your own store so you or your own
storefront rather
could work and have it rockin through
this book should we call it like a is it
an office or like a studio loft it is
upstairs
I think office probably is appropriate
my office studio sounds cool though and
notice I I called this a studio and it
is a recording studio but it just feels
cool to say student yeah my studio is
like a rapper sometimes it's a stew I'm
in the studio yeah I think my office hey
do you think as I'm if you thought about
it yet as the boys are getting older
like say you're like whatever's
happening the clover tribe you're just
maintaining whatever
it's the boys get older you think you're
gonna just continue like the clothes are
gonna get a little bigger in vision I
don't know because I I have thought
about that like well I want to so like
when my kids are bigger but honestly my
kids are the ones that get like the
prints that don't sell because it's like
I'm sewing for everyone else and if they
even say like like people are like oh my
gosh your boys probably just have like
the best wardrobe and I'm like well
ledger house Lincoln's hand-me-downs
when it's like I could easily get the
stitching on those is awful it is pork
he's like my my legs cause the breeze is
coming through which like I could easily
sober him but it's like I have these all
these orders and so I honestly don't see
myself like stopping because like
they're bigger um
just a piece of me is like well I I
don't know I'll just have to see where
it goes cuz it's like when they're in
school like I could go back to work but
it's like what if this is like what if
this is gonna be my work only and you
don't even have to have it planned out
that's the greatest part is you can
really leave it up to that like what if
like I'm gonna see where this goes and
I'm gonna keep this momentum if you
would have told me so what am i three
and a half years later that I was
quitting my job to do this full-time I
would have been like did something like
crazy happen like why like is everything
okay in my life yeah it's
seriously if someone would have told me
like this is gonna happen I would have
been like what cuz it never I don't know
it's weird how life works it's like you
can never ever planned out but you don't
need to know and that's so cool I think
um I can just see like a shift in my
podcast even about like doing more like
self-care and self-love and things like
that versus I feel like the podcasts
even the same same podcasts like I can't
really say which ones because I don't
have them this off my head but um they
used to be so like work work work gig
gig gig like we're doing this this this
and now they're like we're starting to
slow down and it's like and in my life
it's like okay I'm just gonna start
slowing down that's so weird
no I noticed that too it's kind of like
everybody's kind of on the same boat
yeah and then they're like okay we've
realized the same thing about the same
time you're realizing it yeah and it's
weird to like my customers too like if I
announce like I'm gonna take a couple
you know a break or I'm so sorry like my
turnaround time is I'm gonna be a couple
days late like I feel like in the
beginning and it might have just been
like my personal standards like I feel
like they would be mad if I did that
mm-hmm but I feel like now they're like
take the time for yourself like like
you're so you're doing great like
they're so encouraging like I posted a
story which I'm trying to show more on
my face on yeah on Instagram stories
things like that cuz I'm I'm just I've
always been a pretty like self-conscious
person I don't like being like in front
of the camera I feel like I'm awkward
and I recorded myself yesterday saying
how amazing like cuz I dropped a Lincoln
off for school yesterday and it was like
I didn't have to rush to work mm-hmm
I went and I like enjoyed like just
having one kid because Ledger's never
had like one-on-one time with me ever
I can't think unless Lincoln's like
sleeping in or something but um he's
never really gotten like that one-on-one
time and seeing his little face so happy
and like I could joke with them and I'd
stomp in little like petals and target
parking lot and he's like oh I've never
been eight normally
it's like I get in and I get out and I'm
like you know because you're always
going yeah I can't really soak in those
like moments and so I put that on my
Instagram story yesterday and the amount
of people that were messaging me saying
we're so proud and happy for you and
we're so excited like you've worked so
hard for this and like I reading him I
was like oh my gosh like this community
that I have is so rad like it's it's so
incredible how you can start to be so
vulnerable about things like it like you
can once you have a community like gosh
I hope you guys aren't mad at me but
like I wasn't able to get the order done
and like what are you talking about yeah
where we want what's best for you
they're like you're worth the wait is
what people say you know like oh my gosh
I weren't the way like that's so cool
like it I'm an emotional person as it is
but even just talking about it I'm just
like oh like I feel one thing that like
really opened my eyes was that small
shop Saturday event that I had which
I've had like events before where like
you know people are waiting in line and
stuff and my my stuff sells out really
fast like that's so cool but when I
looked at that event and it's almost
like my world stopped for a second
because I had worked on this like
organizing it and sewing all this stuff
for so long and I had looked back and at
one point the entire room like I had a
line like waiting for me and I
remembered for the things that I made
like I stayed up late for I cut I so I
cut again I packaged I put tags on like
I do it all I looked back and at a point
I'm like this is why I do this like the
amount of stress that I had leading up
to this event it was gone
like I was like oh my gosh I like look
over there like I'm acting it out but it
was so amazing oh that's good I mean it
is not within an hour it's super
important that you're able to like
you're such a busybody but it is super
important and it's way cooler that
you're at this point in your life - as
just like an aware person that you can
be like no cool yeah look at this like
this is happening right now I'm like for
me like for myself this must be similar
to
one time well not one time but I've been
in clubs where I'm DJing and I would see
people in the crowd who used to like
jump me or beat me up and I'm like this
is now you're listening to my stuff like
you had to pay to get in here
thinks right like it's I'm
sure it's not exactly because just how
like things come around is like I have
customers that have kids now that I
would have never thought like we didn't
like each other in high school we don't
like each other in middle school and now
it's like they're part of my community a
part of my tribe I'm selling for like
they trust me to sew clothes for their
kids their babies their pride and joy
they're putting their babies in it that
I made it's like and I would have never
thought some of the people like I never
thought I would have even been friends
with them or anything right it's funny
you grow up and you know staying in the
small town we have if you look at like
say Instagram people who like move away
like you got to get away from your
hometown or whatever and I think you
kind of get older and you kind of start
to realize you like wait what is it what
didn't I like and you start letting
others to change you start allowing
yourself to change and then you have
interactions with people and you're like
wait I mean remember why I thought that
I didn't like you or no like I thought
you didn't like me and I what I thought
you were awesome or the amount of energy
it takes to hate somebody or like to not
like somebody right like like let go so
that's been like a I don't know if it's
just as I'm getting older or like this I
don't know the self work that I've done
on myself but it's like all of it yeah I
mean customers that I never thought it's
so I'm like it's so cool like hi you
want a plate like where's your kids
bring with me my best friend's it's it's
so cool cuz it's like you never would
have thought like you never even talked
to them after high school or something
um so yeah well you're in a beautiful
spot in your life right now that's for
sure I feel like I'm excited for the
future do you have any sort of the
coming let's say year - what are you
thinking for clover tribe like what do
you want obviously not just like sales
goals but like what do you want to
represent going for it
you want to continue to push out with
clover tribe in the next few years so I
feel like I've always had to put like a
cap on my stuff because I am like a
one-man show and so I've always had to
put like a cap on stuff so I can't offer
things to everyone and people get sad or
things sell out so fast and people are
messaging me like oh I'm so sad I didn't
get it and so I think going forward now
that I am doing this full-time I would
love to be able to like if if somebody
wants something or they want like a
custom or something like that reach out
to me and I will like I have a little
bit more time now and like I want to be
able to offer more to people but I also
I feel like when I started this business
it was there was a lot of like
competition and I will say I felt kind
of into it too it's like oh you know
she's doing this and you know you were
kind of like oh I don't know yeah you
got the idea first or something or like
oh she's you know sewing these or oh
she's doing this and I feel like in the
past I I've never really been like I'm a
competitive person like working out and
stuff like that but not really like in
this sense I just I don't know no I
totally get what you mean it's it's
definitely you know I just think of
things like Facebook and Instagram where
if like if you're if you were sewing
something and then someone else who has
a similar business you'd post like the
same thing what the heck yeah so I feel
like in the past I will say like I'll
own it I'll I maybe did do that or I did
do that for sure not even maybe but now
it's like I don't even it's not
competition no it's like let's just
build each other up like if I can't do
this you can do this like let's be a
team yeah I see that that's what I've
been it's really cool I've been working
I've worked with DJs and stuff like for
many years in different houses musicians
been working with more and more
musicians and like we're kind of like
trying to we're looking forward into our
future of like what are we doing around
here for our community for the music
scene and it's this like across the
board all these guys I'm working with
they're like oh we're all together like
we want to oh you're a rapper you're
this you're at that like we're working
together we're getting on the same bill
like it's no competition no or even like
I'm sure you can relate like I can't I
don't have time to do this order
or I know somebody has the same fabric
like I have local gals that I I can
bounce stuff off of like local friends
that's so - that I'm like hey I'm not
able to do this like can you do this and
it's so nice to like knowing the
community yeah and they're gonna show
out that cool I appreciate that and I'm
not gonna and not talk yeah we're
on the same page we think that I think
that like we kind of grew up Facebook is
such as still a new thing and social
media and all that stuff we kind of grew
up and we accidentally kept our like
high school cliques for a little too
long with Facebook and maybe we like
grew out of like who exactly was in them
but there still is clicky on
Facebook and it bleeds over into
communities and it's just not super
healthy so I'm glad that more people are
like realizing I don't want to do that I
want to contribute in the best way like
I'm not trying to be a competition like
at all and that's what I mean I do kind
of see it in this community still but I
hope like over the next year or two that
I can just help people or help team up
with people and I don't want drama like
nothing like that it's like and I do
have a pretty cool little crowd of small
shop owners that we all do like
different stuff and supporting them and
getting together doing events things
like that it's so cool like yeah I still
haven't been to one of those but I feel
like I've heard of them like you told me
a little bit about them it sounds like a
really cool thing they're so cool is it
like just multiple businesses that get
together yeah so we each person does
like something different handmade or I
mean I have a couple close friends that
does like up cycled flannels or
distressed denim or my other friend does
um doormats or I have another friend
that sews and I feel like a photographer
like I have so many and I I think
they're all like my good friends now
like my good friend community is like
huge it's like we're all just like a
little business like it's so cool and I
can bounce ideas off of them and so I
hope to going forward I can have more
like little business meetings with these
people - because I know even just like
when you and I get together it's like
when I talk to you I get
like inspired and I hope you feel the
same but I'm definitely I get inspired
and I'm like yes like yes that's you
know and so I think those little like
meetings too with like my little
business people or if somebody has like
you know an idea that they have that
they don't really know how to go about
it like the last three and a half years
it's been trial and error with so many
things like how to balance stuff
websites how did you orders like I would
get up to over a hundred pending orders
at a time and I'm like how do I deal
with this like and it's been a pretty
good learning curve for myself and so I
know like my friends will bounce things
off of me as I bounce things off of them
and I hope like going forward if
somebody has an idea how do I get this
started how do I go about this like I
would love to be that person there's
people can ask you there's people next
to you with the answer it's like and
that's yeah I mean even in my world in
the music world if there's things I
don't know I can hit up one of my homies
like hey have you worked with this
program for sure like yeah I'll come
over tomorrow or like ham stuck on this
thing it's it's great I think realizing
that you have a community rather than
thinking you're just fighting everybody
or it yeah early conversation it's like
oh my gosh I would love like if I don't
have something like to send them over to
you or like I've said do that all
together um wedding so I don't I don't
deejay weddings and at this point for
the foreseeable future
but I luckily I have over over the few
years I have multiple DJ it's that I've
worked with that have done wedding
something cool you would you would do
well and so I can forward those people
yeah and and so if someone asked me to
do wedding no I'm do you feel like any
competition really anymore I I'm not
really I've never really been super
competitive and I've just always been
super my own thing so I always I'm
delusional and thinking that nobody's in
my lane though that's probably what it
is I'm like yeah you're not competition
because I'm just do my own thing I'm
crazy
I just toot my own horn but but I always
I always say this thing to myself and I
say it out loud here to you in the
studio is you couldn't copy them if you
tried like like when I'm like making a
beat or if someone's account sounds like
this or if I'm taking a sample or I'm
listening say I'm listening to Red Hot
Chili Peppers to get inspiration and I'm
writing a song and it's like the same
BPM as the song the Red Hot Chili
Peppers song well sometimes to be like
man I can't copy the what am i doing I'm
getting too much info from here but it's
I always end with you couldn't copy them
if you tried that's good and that kind
of unwinds your cuz you like oh
yeah what am I even going for you know
cuz I do have like other they don't so
baby clothes per se but I do have other
people that I get like inspo like even
just how they like take pictures and
things like that like that's been a huge
thing on like Instagram for me I don't
see it as competition though or like
they could be doing the same thing as I
do and it's not like I'm ever like oh
yeah like I don't know there's so much
that if we just like look at what look
at everything that we've built together
you know like all the information that
we don't have as individuals but when we
combine it together and like what do you
know about this there's the thing on
your wall that said every single person
you meet knows something you don't
I love that you enter into every
conversation with that you're just super
happy to meet everybody
yeah that's crazy yeah instead of just
being like so oh well especially like
Parenthood oh my gosh
like walking into it as if you you know
this thing and they probably don't yeah
I listen to Nona's podcast and I mean
mom Gill oh my gosh right
oh my god it's like what what is that
like like is it like when you post
something is it comeback or um it's more
just like everything you do and and
sometimes like I know for me like
something that's worked out for me like
I just want to offer advice or like some
people don't like that or vice versa to
like like I get that say like you know
when I'm like some people just want to I
want to bent and and the person's like
oh maybe you need to do this this and
this right and it's like okay I like
literally just wanted to have like a
little mental breakdown real quick use
your position for the moment but yeah
mom guilt those crazy like I feel like
we're getting better about it like it's
getting more like sell for like
awareness about like you know
breastfeeding formula-feeding
co-sleeping sleeping in the crib blah
blah blah blah blah like things like
that I feel like everything's it used to
be
like oh wow you're doing that like I
know for me like I have my kids or I had
my kids sleep in the crib from day one
and people like oh my gosh
you don't care about them and I'm like
because that was everything I know
seriously though I'm like it's their bed
but like people would literally say that
or like the fact that I work out of the
house or something like that that's been
a huge thing too or I know even like
self mom guilt too though cuz I yeah for
sure for sure that's a huge thing like
for me um I know like dropping Lincoln
off at preschool sounds so dumb like
dropping him off and picking him up and
things like that like you're having to
coordinate somebody else to do that mom
guilt from me it's like I see all these
other moms getting to pick and drop off
their kids every single day like I'm not
getting to do that so that was a huge
part of like just myself mom guilt I
just used preschool for an example
because it's like babe it's preschool
but it's like certain things like um I'm
trying to think of another example um I
think it's just kind of like a lot of
like thinking that they're thinking this
about you is it sort of like that yeah
that's like that or I know like with
Lincoln for example because you think
like K one kid is like I mean you can
you can be such a good mom with one kid
you have one kid to worry about and
Lincoln was a pretty good baby and so
like things that work with him it's like
Oh like you know do this and maybe it's
not like I ever like really guilted yeah
I'm trying to put myself in like did I
ever judge people and it's like maybe
like in my head I'm like oh gosh now
that I have two kids though holy
it's like I mean they they control me I
do what they say at this point it's like
keeping him alive right like this one's
breathing we're good Ledger's eating dog
food I'm like oh it's Brody right what
a doctor is that gluten-free dog food
right I swear before it's like you know
people would maybe be like because I
even see myself like oh wow like they're
letting their kid eat dog food that's
kind of weird
but now that I have two kids and it
humbled me up a little bit I don't know
it's like yeah a dog food you're dealing
with what's coming at you that's what a
lot of people are I mean Ledger's so
wild and things that didn't work with I
will say two kids two are so different
so different like you can think you have
it all mastered with one and the other
kid will just I mean he's so ledger so
good right they're good in different
ways like they're different
Shaylee has her nephews we always call
Pete and repeat because like whatever
the whatever the big one does a little
one is obviously the shadow yeah you
know I feel like it's like they could be
fine and then they see each other in
like we're gonna do some shipment
we're gonna be I will say
ledger um he wants so bad to be like
Lincoln but he's only one like he just
turned worse so he doesn't have like I
mean he will get up and he will climb
exam the coordination but he doesn't
have the coordination or like the and so
he he's a wild one and I I feel like all
of my friends like with the second it's
like they're like oh yeah that's the
second like they're just wild but having
two wild boys that are and it's just
like putting out fires constantly like
if one's not happy the other ones not
like one's happy the other ones not
happy it's just I don't know it's well
there's there's no damn mom guilt here
to be found in the life of chaos Anders
that's for sure
divvied up fooling around here you know
I ate it all
I did actually this morning I'm not
kidding as I was so uh here's here's my
extent you have two children I had a
problem with two stray cats this morning
this is how different life is I was I
was meditating with out my back garage
door because it was I think it maybe was
sprinkling something but I wanted the
outside and I was like 15 minutes in and
then to the left over here so there's a
lumberyard over here and I just heard
like the hissing out of nowhere and
obviously it pulled me on my meditation
and how's that Hey like made a noise
because I knew that it was these two
stray cats and they
sprint out and then they're just like
sitting in front of me for 450 feet for
the rest of my meditation and then to be
honest the rest of meditation was just
sitting there thinking about these cats
acted well because I have because of the
nature of Who I am I've already named
these cats before prior to this moment
because there's a few did you see that I
had a stray dog the other day no what do
you do oh yeah so yours no I mean I
called the check on it cuz I had a bring
it to the Humane Society it was so sad
but um yeah so for we had a dog show up
on her front and it wanted to be in the
family we named it Milo okay he's got a
name yeah he's got a name and I left the
blanket like with because we have two
dogs too so we have two dogs in two
babies and we're selling our house so I
mean a piece of me it was like oh that's
really sad like I wish we could you know
take it to the bed or wash it I even
asked Jake I go can we like give it a
little path and he's like we don't even
Bay their own dogs the other dogs back
are you kidding me your boss it there's
outside the window looking granted Milo
is tiny and they're labs but it was
funny we bring it to I was bringing it
to the main Society in the middle of
trying to look at all these spaces the
other day still had a kick-ass day too
by the way and I had it although I I did
like like like can I call and check up
on them and so we left like a blanket
and Lincoln's like that's our dog he's
blanket not like but like this doggy
really wanted it and he was really sad
because we're dropping it off music okay
I know but yeah finally he's like why
would you be giving and getting rid of
this dog anyway there he did he was like
at first so he's like we're not keeping
it cuz it was kind of ugly
I had like I'm a really bad under bite
and so the teeth are really spiky and so
Lincoln was like genuinely no Lincoln
was like genuinely scared though about
the dog he was like uh he said mom the
teeth but I'm like it's just got a
gnarly everybody what's this meadow
tooth doggy he's just got some
hitchhikers hanging out
no yes well my straight out story well
we are getting up here in time my friend
I feel like we've got a pretty good
overview of who taya is yeah what clover
tribe is I worked my ass off you
certainly have congratulations on on
everything that you've done and what's
what's coming here now your future
what's going forward so so so what's
next in the in the very what's right
night so you got you got a space yes I
got a space I am moving in within the
next couple weeks and then I'm just
gonna I do pretty big website launches
but I did kind of like a poll of what my
customers kind of want to see and so I'm
gonna do my plan obviously things change
but my mental plan is I'm going to do
monthly website launches but in between
those monthly website launches
I'm gonna still be launching things I'm
just gonna have like a big website
launch ones unless cool and then I would
love to do more local events I only
think I got a couple in last year I
think I did three local events last year
I already have one planned for February
I think it's 20th at the color bar okay
color bars having a grand opening and so
I have that one and then I'm just gonna
try to be scheduling local pop-ups and
stuff and hopefully I'm super-stoked
I'll be able to offer local pickup when
I'm in my is my studio my office space
just name it whatever you want my office
space I'll be able like and not only
that because I've had local pick up
places before but I get to like meet my
customers because before they would go
pick it up locally at a local spot and
now it's like I get face like face to
face interaction I get to shake their
hand I get to thank them for buying the
item I get to maybe meet their kids like
things like that I'm so stoked for its
absolutely but so that's so fulfilling I
think we kind of forget why we do things
and that's a reminder of like oh this is
why I do this this I was talking about
Target i I see this baby
and it's happened multiple times since
or people show up to my events and their
kid will be like decked out in my stuff
and that's so cool but the very first
time I seen somebody and it was I was
pretty at a low like stress or a low
point high stress like that day hmm
I remember I was just you know trucking
along and Target and I see a baby from
across the way in a shopping cart
wearing an outfit that I I like I mean I
will say like blood sweat and tears not
home blood because I cut myself watched
it right but you know what I mean like I
see it and I hold you out of your
right oh my I was like this is why I do
it yeah this is why you having a bad day
you're like huh I'm going to go story
I'm going to target I'm getting all
these things then also you know yeah
like how cool is that
I even went up to the person I'm like hi
like I'm so excited
I made that like did you just pick up
your baby right that's awful yeah okay
no it's my clothes I mean the clothes
right I'm like hey like it's so cool cuz
I love babies yeah love babies and I
think just like seeing kids in the
clothes that I made like you can only
imagine how yeah real cool and you get
in you get to meet the people too so how
are you gonna handle that
do people just message you on social
medias or on webpage when it's planning
on having at least two days a week if
not three that I am in my office space
and I basically when I send the
notification that it's ready for pickup
they it'll have the instructions of like
you know we're open Monday Wednesday
Friday from this time to this yeah
that's a good way to yeah so cuz right
now I probably I mean right now I'm
shipping a hundred percent of my items
but locally when I had the local
drop-off I was shipping probably 70% so
I'll get to like actually like me 30
percent if not more the people I mean
that's fulfilling for them too I bet I
gave him from the customer experience
yeah yeah cuz I had kind of like you
know somebody over social media right
and like meeting that I had that when I
did those you matter hoodies for a while
because I was doing a lot of custom
orders for that and that was like I mean
that was something
was like way too much for me I just
didn't it was great that I did it but it
was cool like when I was down with it I
could text him like okay hey I'm finally
done with it thanks for being so patient
yeah that cool and then I can go like
their house and drop it off they're just
like they're looking at it oh it's so
cool I mean I you know those those took
me a lot of a lot of my time but not
even a little bit of the amount of time
that you put in or like when people will
message me or post like videos of them
opening like the package that they got
in the mail so yeah going forward that's
my plan in the next like month or so
kind of fast forward or fast-track
through the next month I'm going to move
in I'm going to do website launch with
all new products all new prints and
stuff and then I will have a local pop
up in February okay and I hope I'm not
gonna rush getting like MySpace all set
up and stuff because I want to be sewing
um obviously but I'm gonna do little
bits at a time and eventually I hope to
you know get that spot like dialed in oh
and you're you're setting up your girl
cave - oh yeah you got you can make it
your own that's your I know I'm so
excited and it's like one thing when
it's at your house it's like I don't
know yeah it is a different your house
but then you go like to work for me yeah
yeah and you can be fully engaged you
don't have to be pulled out but like
running upstairs oh yeah that's the
thing is like it's always been like
broken up like I do a little bits at a
time and then after a bedtime but it's
like then I need to sleep because I have
to get up for work and you're ready at
6:30 in the morning yeah I mean I'm
someone who's a huge advocate of like I
look at like cubicles and stuff people
who are pulled out like they're working
on their stuff but someone could lean
over and be like hey can you send me
that email or blah blah or they have to
respond to emails right away for me that
would that would not be good I have to
be able to like have my time to have
some focus yeah I know like in this like
in my business because that's how it was
like at my work and I was fine with that
um cuz with that work it's like there's
always gonna be work to be done kind of
thing but with this it's like okay I can
I can do it like oh my gosh I'm just so
excited I'm excited for you okay so once
a website's up
listeners what's the website is a clover
tribe or is it clever dry clover tribe
calm and then my Instagram is a clip
tribe ok yeah
awesome thank you well let's finish off
junker I love podcast listeners this has
been taya Sanders of clover tribe and
Jacob rhymes with junkie I'd love we
hope you have a wonderful day
we hope that you don't add into mom
drama we don't believe in that yes and
we also hope you drink a damn glass of
water if you have it
you